

DATA SCIENTIST

40 Allées de Tourny, 33000 Bordeaux, France

📳 (+33)6 16 24 58 68 | 💌 thomas.lentali@gmail.com | 🛅 thomas-lentali | 🕥 tlentali | 💃 tlentali | 🖹 tlentali

Summary

Data Scientist with 6+ years experience specializing in machine learning applied to a broad-spectrum of field like personalization/recommender system, search engine relevancy, bot detection, NLP, computer vision, financial fraud, gambling addiction detection, lifetime value prediction. My aim is to turn abstract knowledge into real world application and solving tools. I am an open minded nerd who act to stay sharp in his domain through helping my peers (top 1% on Stackoverflow in 2021), competitions (Kaggle competition expert) and open source contributions. And even if I am clearly driven by the data science field, I also defend the #1 Google ML Rule "Don't be afraid to launch a product without machine learning".

Work Experience _____

Betclic Group Bordeaux, France

Data Scientist Jun. 2019 - current

- Sport betting and casino personalization/recommender system (hybrid recommendations approaches).
- Anti Money Laundering detection (ACAMS Certified Anti-money Laundering Specialist).
- Responsible gambling (addiction behavior) detection (classification).
- Lifetime value prediction (BTYD).

Using: Python (Pandas, Scikit-learn, Pytorch, Tensorflow/Keras, Shap, Pytest, Great Expectation), Apache Airflow, AWS Sagemaker, Snowflake.

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST ADVISOR Nov. 2018 - Mai. 2019

- · Massive customer clustering.
- Bot detection (pattern analysis).
- · Sentiment analysis (Natural Langage Processing).
- Object detection in picture (Mask-RCNN, MSCOCO dataset).

Using: Python (Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, Shap, Luigi), SQL, Apache Hadoop Hive.

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

 DATA SCIENTIST
 Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2018

- · Search engine relevance.
- Products recommendation engine.
- Algorithms evaluation (A/B testing).
- · Focus on website's KPI improvment.

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

Data Scientist Intern

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- Marketing targeting: behavioral analysis and improvement of the search engine relevence through AB test, proof of concept personnalisation client (classification and clustering).
- Geographical data: Purchase forecasting by geographic zone.
- · Statistical analysis: data enrichment with INSEE database, implementation and developement of geocoding tool.
- Intern innovation contest: Setting of a new operationnal service for the client, forcasting system of product storage to allow express delivery.

Idaia Group Bordeaux, France

Data Scientist Intern

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

• Sourcing, implementation and development of machine learning tools (mainly multiclass classification) in Python and Scala into Apache Spark large-scale data framework.

Using: Python (Scikit-learn, Numpy, Scipy, NLTK), Scala, Spark (MLlib).

Education _____

Bordeaux University

Bordeaux, France

MSC. APPLIED MATHEMATICS Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2016

• Optimization, operation research, machine learning, statistics, C++, Python, SQL

Toulon University Toulon, France

BSC. APPLIED MATHEMATICS

Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2012

• Statistics, probability, econometry, R, Matlab/Octave

Toulon University Toulon, France

BSC. PURE MATHEMATICS Sep. 2008 - Jul. 2011

• Algebra, analysis, topology, mesure theory, graph theory, C, Matlab/Octave, Wolfram Mathematica